# Ángel Esteban Féliz Ferreras

Senior Data Analyst

Dominican Rep., Santo Domingo angel.esteban.feliz@gmail.com angelfeliz.com





#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Reporting Analyst with 2 years' experience using R to process and create business reports in formats such as Excel, Word, Power Point, and html. Proven experience integrating ad hoc regular expressions to transform, extract and validate text data in data pipelines to find abnormalities and automate repetitive tasks; improving reporting accuracy, reducing waiting times and opening new possibilities to empower decision makers. Autodidactic, self-motivated, inquisitive, and eager to apply data science techniques to create business value and increase ROI for your company.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Airbnb Dashboard

Data visualization, machine learning for exploration, Power BI, ggplot2 and ggtext

# **CERTIFICATES**

- Data Scientist with R Data Camp 2023
- R Programmer Data Camp 2022
- Data Analyst with R Data Camp 2022
- Text Mining with R Data Camp 2022
- Importing & Cleaning Data with R Data Camp 2022

#### **LANGUAGES**

• English: Full professional proficiency

• Spanish: Native

#### REFERENCES

• Ing. Luis Colón Informatic Manager - Security Force

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Leasing Reporting Analyst (Remotely)

PHOENIX TOWER INTERNATIONAL | 04/2022 - Present

- Accelerated report changing process to be 60% faster by implementing coding standards to improve code readability and implementing the qit control version
- Automated 3 key business **Spread Sheet reports** generation by using the *openxlsx*
- Improved KPI report accuracy by implementing data automatic validation and managing report dependencies.

# **Leasing Reporting Analyst** (Remotely)

PHOENIX TOWER INTERNATIONAL | 04/2021 - 03/2022

- Implemented a data quality control report to validate 42 key business rules in tenant leases across 17 countries, avoiding potential billing problems.
- · Improved sales pipeline report to track changes, identify stopping points and facilitate team communication which helped to execute 25% more projects in 2022 first quarter.
- · Managed team report doubts from all leasing team, located in United States, Ireland, Italy, France, Cyprus, Mexico, Chile, and Dominican Republic.

## Data Analyst Junior (Santo Domingo)

SECURITY FORCE | 10/2020 - 03/2021

- Consolidated tables with 800 proper names with diverse typing problems to improve employee attendance report.
- Designed and created ad hoc Excel forms with validation rules for data entry.
- Automated Power BI dashboards to track online customer surveys.

## **SKILLS**

General	Data Manipulation		Functional Programming	
	Data Cleaning		Bootstrapping	
	Text Mining		Network Analysis	
	Regular Expressions		Interactive Visualization	
	Statistical Analysis		Package Development	
Languages	R, SQL, Linux Bash, html, css			
<b>Control version tools</b>	Git, renv, Github, Azure Repos			
Reporting tools	Quarto, Excel, Word, Power Point, Power Bl			
R libraries	tidyverse	ggplot2	stringdist	plotly
	tidytext	data.table	lubridate	tidymodels

# **EDUCATION**

#### INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE SANTO DOMINGO

Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Engineering (3.91 GPA) 2017 - 2021

# INSTITUTO TÉCNICO SUPERIOR COMUNITARIO

Associate Degree in Logistics (3.84 GPA) 2014 – 2016